<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
	<p>
    Different implementation guides will have different settings used in their rendering.  However, most implementation guides published using the HL7 IG templates will have a
    common set of behavior.  This page provides an overview of the elements found in most implementation guides.
  </p>
  <a name="general"> </a>
  <h3>General appearance</h3>
  <p>
    These characteristics apply to most/all pages within the IG
  </p>
  <a name="colors"> </a>
  <h4>Color scheme</h4>
  <p>The top and bottom of all HL7 IGs have color schemes that are specific to product family:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>FHIR IGs use a <span style="background-color:#ad1f2f; color:white">red</span> background</li>
    <li>CDA  IGs use a <span style="background-color:#2E8B57; color:white">green</span> background</li>
    <li>V2   IGs use a <span style="background-color:#2E40FF; color:white">blue</span> background</li>
    <li>Non-family-specific IGs use a <span style="background-color:#505050; color:white">grey</span> background</li>
    <li>Non-HL7 IGs use a <span style="background-color:#7b1fad; color:white">purple</span> background by default, though this can be overridden by organization-specific templates</li>
  </ul>
  <a name="header"> </a>
  <h4>Header</h4>
  <p>
    
  </p>

  <a name="structures"> </a>
  <h3>Structure Definitions</h3>

  <a name="sdviews"> </a>
  <h4>Model 'views'</h4>
  <p>
    A structure definition is made up of a collection of <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}elementdefinition.html">ElementDefinitions</a> that describe the individual data
    elements that make up the model.  When an implementation guide displays those elements, there are often different subsets of the elements that are of interest to the
    reader.  For this reason, implementation guides offer up different 'views' of the model, each of which exposes different subsets of elements.  This view-based approach
    is used for both the <a href="#sdtables">table views</a> and the <a href="#sddicts">data dictionaries</a>.
  </p>
  <p>
    There are up to four different types of table view, though not all will appear in every implementation guide:
  </p>
  <ul>
    <li><b>Differential</b> - used to indicate what is 'different' between the parent model for the structure definition and the current
      model.  In general, only those properties of the element that have changed will be shown, though some properties are always displayed to provide context.  Element
      properties that are unchanged from the parent model are partially opaque, looking greyish.  Element properties that have been removed from the parent model are
      rendered with strikethrough.  This view shows "what has this profile done?" - it shows the content of the profile, but not necessarily everything that needs to
      be implemented or that is possible to share.</li>
    <li><b>Snapshot</b> - shows the complete set of data elements allowed within the profile.  This is the result of applying all of the changes from the 'differential'
      to the base model.  This view is the largest, as it includes everything that can be represented within the model by a conformant system.  It is useful to understand
      the full context of what's possible, and is often the appropriate view to look at when seeking possible targets when mapping.  Note that the snapshot only drills
      down into data types when the model imposes additional constraints on those types.  This means that to see <i>all</i> data elements, the reader must click through
      the data types to see what those types contain.  A full exapansion view that drills down into all data types is not possible because, with extensions, data types
      recurse.  (Even if icons were used to denote recursion, the view would be too overwhelming to be useful for most models.)</li>
    <li><b>Must Support</b> - This is a trimmed-down version of the snapshot that only includes those data elements that are marked as 
      <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}profiling.html#mustsupport">mustSupport</a> - i.e. those where
      the implementation guide requires specific application behavior related to the capture, storage, rendering, transmission, and/or other uses of the element.  This
      view provides a quick scan of some of the most important elements, but is generally less useful than the 'Key elements' view.</li>
    <li><b>Key Elements</b> - This view includes a subset of the elements from the snapshot, including only those elements that need to be considered in some way as part
      of the implementation process.  The criteria that drives whether an element requires additional implementation consideration includes:<br/>
      a) an initial list of elements determined as follows:
        <ul>
          <li>The root element (always includeded)</li>
          <li>All elements that are marked as <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}profiling.html#mustsupport">mustSupport</a></li>
          <li>All elements that are listed in the differential (if the profile says something about them, they're presumed to be important)</li>
          <li>All ancestor elements of those listed above.  E.g. if an element is not mustSupport but contains descendants that are mustSupport, it will be considered a
            'key element', even though support for it is optional because there are implementation considerations if the system chooses to support it.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
  </ul>
  
  <a name="sdtables"> </a>
  <h4>Table Views</h4>
  <p>
    Table views provide a grid-like view of a structure definition, with a hierarchical view of the model supplemented by metadata describing the elements within the model.
  </p>
  
  <a name="sddicts"> </a>  
  <h4>Data Dictionaries</h4>
  
</div>
